DAN KLEIN: So what happens when
you enforce arc consistency?
Is it some magic wand that
solves your CSP?
It's definitely not.
So after enforcing arc consistency, you
can be in a couple of situations.
You can have one solution left.
You can have multiple solutions left,
because of course the CSP may have
multiple solutions remaining, given
the assignment you have so far.
And you can also no solutions
left and not know it.
OK, so here are some configurations.
Let's take a look at them and see
whether or not things are arc
consistent.
All right, so again, these are
all inequality constraints.
This is still map coloring.
How about here?
Let's look at the top one.
Are things consistent?
Well we could check.
Is this arc consistent?
Well, for everything in the
tail does it work out?
Yep.
How about this arc, is it consistent?
Yes.
OK, how about here?
This is the interesting one.
Well, they can't both be green, right?
But if you assign green to the tail,
then you can assign blue in the head,
and if assign blue to the tail, you
can assign green to the head.
So this one here, it's arc consistent.
Are there any solutions left in there?
Yes.
How many?
There are two.
So arc consistency certainly will not
narrow you down to one solution.
How about down here?
Is this thing arc consistent?
Well, let's check the arcs.
OK, is this arc consistent?
If I assign red at the tail,
how about the head?
I'll assign blue.
If I assign blue at the tail,
I'll assign red at the head.
How about the other direction?
Also consistent.
All right, great, the whole
thing is arc consistent.
That CSP is arc consistent.
Are there any solutions to this CSP?
No.
Arc consistency does not
detect all failures.
It only detects a subclass
of failures.
In this particular case, to detect the
failure I would need to consider three
variables at once.
Arc consistency only
traffics in pairs.
Because of this, arc consistency is only
part of a backtracking search.
It's a filtering algorithm.
If I enforce arc consistency, I have to
do it after every assignment in a
backtracking search.